<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Dibyajyoti Jena</title>
    <link>https://coolman-spaceman.github.io/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Dibyajyoti Jena</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 10:33:26 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://coolman-spaceman.github.io/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Retinal Fundus Image Enhancement</title>
      <link>https://coolman-spaceman.github.io/projects/retina/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 10:33:26 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://coolman-spaceman.github.io/projects/retina/</guid>
      <description>Retinal Fundus Image Enhancement With Image Decomposition and Visual Adaptation  A random calming image to show I have no experience in writing content  Retinal fundus photography is a non-invasive method to check for symptoms and other features related to diseases like diabetic retinopathy, age-related macular degeneration, cardiovascular disease. The main features to look out for are the vascular structure, lesions, optic disc, microaneurysms, etc. These depend on high quality fundus images to be processed properly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>List of major projects</title>
      <link>https://coolman-spaceman.github.io/projects/list/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 16:49:19 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://coolman-spaceman.github.io/projects/list/</guid>
      <description>This page contains a list of major projects I have done after 2021, most of which have been in Computer Vision, Machine Learning, Communication topics, etc. Each entry has a brief description of the project like the tech stack used and so on. The links to individual project pages will be included later; The list will grow with time!
Information Flow Across Neural Network Layers   This project aims to decode the black box nature of neural networks and provide insights on how information is processed over the layers of a network based on many metrics such as information capacity.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
