<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Dibyajyoti Jena</title>
    <link>https://coolman-spaceman.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Dibyajyoti Jena</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 10:33:26 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://coolman-spaceman.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Retinal Fundus Image Enhancement</title>
      <link>https://coolman-spaceman.github.io/projects/retina/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 10:33:26 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://coolman-spaceman.github.io/projects/retina/</guid>
      <description>Retinal Fundus Image Enhancement With Image Decomposition and Visual Adaptation  A random calming image to show I have no experience in writing content  Retinal fundus photography is a non-invasive method to check for symptoms and other features related to diseases like diabetic retinopathy, age-related macular degeneration, cardiovascular disease. The main features to look out for are the vascular structure, lesions, optic disc, microaneurysms, etc. These depend on high quality fundus images to be processed properly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Post4</title>
      <link>https://coolman-spaceman.github.io/posts/post4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2023 09:41:29 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://coolman-spaceman.github.io/posts/post4/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started With Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://coolman-spaceman.github.io/posts/post3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2023 21:34:21 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://coolman-spaceman.github.io/posts/post3/</guid>
      <description>A random calming image to show I have no experience in writing content  They said the hardest part of the flight is taking off. Guess we’ll never know if we don’t go to the runway.
And why did I decide to start a blog post on machine learning when there is literally a million listed, authentic resources out there all over YouTube and MOOC websites. That is exactly the reason why.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>List of major projects</title>
      <link>https://coolman-spaceman.github.io/projects/list/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 16:49:19 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://coolman-spaceman.github.io/projects/list/</guid>
      <description>This page contains a list of major projects I have done after 2021, most of which have been in Computer Vision, Machine Learning, Communication topics, etc. Each entry has a brief description of the project like the tech stack used and so on. The links to individual project pages will be included later; The list will grow with time!
Information Flow Across Neural Network Layers   This project aims to decode the black box nature of neural networks and provide insights on how information is processed over the layers of a network based on many metrics such as information capacity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 1: Introduction and K-Means</title>
      <link>https://coolman-spaceman.github.io/lectures/lec1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 18:52:07 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://coolman-spaceman.github.io/lectures/lec1/</guid>
      <description>This tutorial assumes some familiarity with basic principles of machine learning, the math and code can be developed on the way.
Machine Learning Learning can be Supervised, Unsupervised, Reinforced and Semi-supervised.
 Reinforcement Learning: Learning with a critic, critic may be wrong at times, maybe stochastic, but different from supervisor in case of supervised learning. Supervisor gives feedback, critic only says yes or no.
 K-Means algorithm:  K as a parameter distance threshold as a parameter  K means crisp decision boundary: grading, fingerprint ROI(Region of Interest)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practical Guide On Training Custom Yolo V3 Model</title>
      <link>https://coolman-spaceman.github.io/posts/post2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2023 09:56:43 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://coolman-spaceman.github.io/posts/post2/</guid>
      <description>Darknet Logo  The YOLO architecture is very similar to any conventional CNN, but training YOLO from scratch for custom images is still a mystery for many. One of the reasons is the initial training dataset problem, we have to annotate each image for its bounding boxes. Then modify the configuration file according to the number of classes we are training for. This tutorial is the best for those who want to start out on YOLO without much coding experience or even knowledge of convolutional neural networks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://coolman-spaceman.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://coolman-spaceman.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello visitor, I am Dibyajyoti Jena, working my way to stay away from Roko&amp;rsquo;s Basilisk.
My undergrad was from IIIT Bhubaneswar, India, in Electronics and Communication (2021), where I learnt my love for good code. I am now pursuing a masters in Communication Engineering.
On the lookout for employment opportunities/internships in the mixed fields of machine learning, deep learning or signal processing and communication. Any future employers are welcome drop a mail at dibyajyotijena47@gmail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Post One</title>
      <link>https://coolman-spaceman.github.io/posts/post1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2023 15:57:15 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://coolman-spaceman.github.io/posts/post1/</guid>
      <description>This is official post one. We will include some code here, syntax highlighting etc.
Trying out changes to see if I am comfortable with uploading live changes to github.
Try a youtube video embedding:
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Post Zero</title>
      <link>https://coolman-spaceman.github.io/posts/post0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2023 15:56:46 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://coolman-spaceman.github.io/posts/post0/</guid>
      <description>Ok this is the first post, lets see if we can include some math here lol
$$ (1 + 1)^2 = 4 $$
Heading one I like Bold Text.
$$f(k) = {n \choose k} p^{k} (1-p)^{n-k}$$
\begin{equation} \begin{pmatrix} 1 &amp;amp; x^1_0 &amp;amp; x^2_0 &amp;amp; \cdots &amp;amp; x^{degree}_0 \\ 1 &amp;amp; x^1_1 &amp;amp; x^2_1 &amp;amp; \cdots &amp;amp; x^{degree}_1 \\ \vdots &amp;amp; \vdots &amp;amp; \vdots &amp;amp; \ddots &amp;amp; \vdots \\ 1 &amp;amp; x^1_n &amp;amp; x^2_n &amp;amp; \cdots &amp;amp; x^{degree}_n \\ \end{pmatrix} \end{equation} \begin{equation} \frac{a}{b} \end{equation}</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
